Welcome back to my page and this is grow
and Grace with KC and if this is your first time
here what we are discussing
are money issues career and
dreams in life so join
me and let's study and face
the realities of life so that we can
be better even better
with our blessings and in this video
we will talk about life
insurance what is life insurance
and By the way I am a certified
financial advisor that means
we have taken exams to
become a legal financial advisor and
now I'm working in fwd all right so that I
have notes because
I really forget I have
short-term memory loss so Alright ah
life insurance what is life
insurance or this is this is the money that
our loved ones can get
in case something happens to
us so first um How can
our loved ones get money in case something happens
to us if
we don't pay anything so of course we will
pay something so it depends on
us if quarterly Mon
We pay annually and what
we pay is called premium Okay so
the premium is not the same because it
depends on how big
our approved amount of our
insurance is
and there are many factors that will affect
the amount okay first of all
our age So if you are younger you are a little
smaller the premium you will pay is smaller
because you are still far from 75
years old no So if you are closer to
that of course you are older the
premium will be more expensive The same will
affect our premium
our health condition So
if you are younger you are healthier You do not have any
illnesses
that you are
currently being treated for or a history of
illness
your premium will also be cheaper because you are at a lower risk of
Of course for death and critical
illness one of the things that will affect the
amount of the premium is the financial
capability of the client So as a financial
advisor we will
help you
assess your budgeting or
um How do we um How can we
find the perfect and um suitable
policy for you that you can
maintain because once you are not  You can
maintain him Of course
the insurance will be gone he will be cut
okay I said earlier the insurance is
not the same so it depends
on the client no we will help
ah based on the need
based on the capability of the client so
we will not discuss the different
classes of insurance so we have what is
called term insurance and
permanent insurance so it is based on the
coverage of the insurance no So if term
insurance it only has a certain
period of time that you are covered by
insurance for example I applied for
insurance is June 26
until and the term I chose is
for one year and So um I am covered when
um the policy started not the
policy was approved on June 26
2024 I was covered by the insurance until
June 26 2025 So if something happens to
me like I die by June 27 2025
I am no longer covered by insurance so
my loved ones will not get anything The
same thing if 5 years 7 years or 10
years within that span only what
you chose  term you will be covered unlike if
permanent no what you applied for is for
permanent life you are covered as long as
you pay your
premium again the permanent is
until you die as long as
you pay your
premium and then there is also um
insurance that is more focused on
insurance really not on death benefits
and critical illness there is also
insurance that is more focused on
investment so we have a separate
video for that so we can understand it better
Okay so there is also um
insurance that is focused on educational
or
retirement there is also for state
protection and we need to know
these four or three people who are inside
a policy so first okay the
financial advisor or the insurance
Agent is the one who will assist you he will
help prove your
policy and you will also
go to him when ah for claim and if you
have questions so yeah you need um
you should also maintain
your relationship with your Agent
so that um your Agent is updated
so he can also help you
when it comes to your um questions and
inquiries about your insurance and then
we need to understand that there is a
policy owner  There is an
insured and there is also a beneficiary
so the policy owner is the one who will make the
policy he is the one who has the right of all the
changes to yours within the policy So
basically he is the one who will be um um it
will be like I am talking directly to
a financial advisor and then um the
insured the insured is the one who can
cycle down
only the beneficiary will have a claim
also the policy owner can claim
other benefits but the death benefits
are and funeral benefits Are claimed by
the beneficiary no So it is possible for the policy
owner and the insured to be one person
only who are the ones who can be the
beneficiaries of the insurance
um your legal spouse take note
legal spouse not in partner you
need that you can prove that you are
married Okay so you will need
documents for that claim and your
legitimate children or illegitimate
children as long as again you can prove
that you are related to the insured and
then um your parents or in Estate you
can
Actually make comp or partnership your
beneficiary to pay not
too much money monthly or
annually or um
quarterly there is a lot of money that
our love can get So  um It's important
that we know how much this will
help us because it's like
you're hiding money but what
your loved ones will get is bigger than what
you've lost, that's what life insurance is and
I totally understand because
I was the same way before I didn't understand it
and I feel like it would just be a burden
on the additional additional What are the
fees but now I kind of regret it I wish
I had started
earlier and made more effort
to understand about insurance because there are a lot
of people who offer insurance like this
here like that But nothing but how am I
like I woke up when I had
a lumbar strain and I thought in my mind it's still my
spine when
I get sick I can't
work anymore or I can't even
study for myself I can't help my family So
how is that so I appreciate it more sometimes we appreciate things agag what's up agag
when I found out
that it was just a strain I
just needed to rest I just needed to
stop lifting heavy things
so that it wouldn't be completely injured
um that's um I also decided to
really study this life insurance
get my own insurance and Uh
also help others
understand this insurance better So
that's why Grow and Grace
with KC is here so we can study the
things that we need that
you know that we didn't before we weren't
exposed especially us Filipinos
we weren't exposed to financial literacy
like that So that's our Goal I hope
you are younger than me or if
you are older than me it's not too late we
can still Ong
um understand We can still Ong
try we can Ong face
the realities of life together so
I hope you understood something
you learned something here in this funny video
about What is life insurance and
um please Stay tuned for our other
videos because um we will explain
our fwd life insurance even more Don't
forget to like and subscribe to our channel
Chel ah Also ah To also help
Please continue this Uh videos and
also We can help more people,
reach more people so that we can better understand
the issues of money, career and our
dreams in life, let's inspire
each other, let's strive to become good
towards God's blessings. Thank you
[Music]